Patrick (Brien) Barr

Carmel, IN 46280 | Email: brien.barr3320@gmail.com | Phone: 317-910-6049 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/brien-barr | GitHub: https://github.com/BrienBarr | Portfolio: https://brienbarr.github.io/react-portfolio/

Summary

Experienced full stack developer with over 3 years experience creating interactive programs for museums and science centers. Over 10 years front end development experience with creating and maintaining corporate site. Adept in and executing strategies to complete projects on time and within budget. Works well in both a team and individual environment. Currently attending the Butler University Executive Coding Bootcamp.

Technical Skills

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Bulma, JavaScript, jQuery, API, Node.js, React, Material-UI, PHP, Visual Studio Code, GitHub, Windows OS, Microsoft Office 365, Adobe Production Software (Premiere, Photoshop, After Effects, Illustrator, Dreamweaver, InDesign), Autodesk 3ds Max, Autodesk AutoCAD LT

Projects

Employee Directory

- Interactive app allowing user to filter employee list by first or last name, and then, sort filtered results using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Node.js, and React.
- Deployed application: https://brienbarr.github.io/employee-directory/
- GitHub repository: https://github.com/BrienBarr/employee-directory

Workout Tracker

- Interactive app allowing user to create a workout and add exercises to that workout or modify and add exercises to the current workout using HTML, CSS, Semantic UI, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, and Heroku.
- Deployed application: https://protected-dusk-68194.herokuapp.com/
- GitHub repository: https://github.com/BrienBarr/Workout-Tracker

Experience

Bowen Technovation

2002-Present

Indianapolis, IN

Promoted to: Full Stack Interactive Developer

2017-Present

- Created and deployed user interactive experiences for museums and science centers
- Responsible for UX/UI design and coding
- Implemented programming for back end server

Promoted to: Website Creation and Maintenance

2003-Present

- Updated corporate website and created new web content for site
- Maintained all in-house computers, network hardware, and printers
- Produced marketing materials for print and web
- Managed all audio/video/interactive content creation and deployment

Assistant Audio/Video Editor

2002-2003

Assisted with all audio and video content editing

Education

Butler Executive Coding Bootcamp - Indianapolis, IN Certificate

Ball State University - Muncie, IN Graduated *Magna Cum Laude*BA Telecommunications/Production Minor in Film Studies